The Estonian Declaration of Independence, formally titled the Manifesto to the Peoples of Estonia (Estonian: Manifest Eestimaa rahvastele), is the founding document which established the independent democratic Republic of Estonia in 1918. Issued during a period of intense political upheaval and foreign occupation in the wake of World War I and the Russian Revolution, the declaration asserted Estonia's national sovereignty and commitment to democratic governance. The declaration announces and explains the separation of Estonia from the Russian Empire.
